Finding Aid for the Edwin Mims Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Correspondence - Incoming
  - C
    - Chadwick, Claude S., (1), Mar. 9, 1956; 15 (Box 15)
    - Chambers, D.L., (1), Aug. 13, 1949; 15 (Box 15)
    - Cheek, F.E., (1), Aug. 23, 1903; 15 (Box 15)
    - Chevrillon, Andre, (1), Aug. 1, 1935; 15 (Box 15)
    - Clement, Rufus E., (1), Mar. 21, 1956; 15 (Box 15)
    - Cole, John N., (1), Sept. 25, 1896; 15 (Box 15)
  - D
    - Dabney, Sam'l B., (1), Nov. 30, 1926; 15 (Box 15)
    - Dabney, Virginius, (2), Feb. 18, 1952, Feb. 19, 1958; 15 (Box 15)
    - Dandridge, E.P., (1), Mar. 22, 1955; 15 (Box 15)
    - Daniels, Jonathan, (1), Feb. 15, 1958 (Box 15)
    - Davidson, Donald, (4), Mar. 20, 1933, Jan. 24, 1934, Oct. 17, 1938, July 6, 1942; 15 (Box 15)
    - Dickey, Frank G., (1), June 7, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
    - Dodd, William E., (1), Mar. 7, 1932; 15 (Box 15)
    - Donovan, H.L., (3), May 25, 1956, July 31, 1956, June 11, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
    - Dowell, Spright, (1), Dec. 7, 1949; 15 (Box 15)
    - Dyer, Art. J., (1), Mar. 20, 1947; 15 (Box 15)
  - E
    - Elliot, Will, (1), June 7, 1926; 15 (Box 15)
    - Erskine, John, (1), Aug. 2, 1941; 15 (Box 15)
  - F
    - Faunce, W.H., (1), Aug. 11, 1927; 15 (Box 15)
    - Few, W.P., (1), n.d.; 15 (Box 15)
    - Field, Ed, (1), June 1, 1951; 15 (Box 15)
    - Fuller, Thomas B., (1), Aug. 4, 1909; 15 (Box 15)
  - G
    - Gay and Bird, (1), Oct. 22, 1904; 15 (Box 15)
    - Gildersleeve, Basil L., (3), Nov. 21, 1905, Sept. 26, 1907, Oct. 25, 1907; 15 (Box 15)
    - Gilkey, Charles W., (1), Oct. 10, 1948; 15 (Box 15)
    - Glasgon, Gilen, (1), June 11, 1942; 15 (Box 15)
    - Greenslet, Fenis, (3), Aug. 14, 1905, Oct. 17, 1905, Dec. 2, 1905; 15 (Box 15)
    - Greever, Garland, (3), Jan. 19, 1915, Apr. 10, 1915, Jan. 3, 1956; 15 (Box 15)
    - Gross, John O., (1), Mar. 15, 1956; 15 (Box 15)
    - Graham, Edward K., (3), Nov. 26, n.d., n.d. (latter two both fragments); 15 (Box 15)
    - Guerry, Alex, (1), Oct. 15, 1948; 15 (Box 15)
  - H
    - Haack, Arno J., (1), Feb. 11, 1949; 15 (Box 15)
    - Hadley, A., (1), May 14, 1912; 15 (Box 15)
    - Harris, Brice, (1), Dec. 18, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
    - Harris, Carra, (1), Sept. 26, 1926; 15 (Box 15)
    - Hart, James, (1), Oct. 24, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
    - Hillard, Addyn, (1), July 25, 1929; 15 (Box 15)
    - Holderness, Marvin E., (1), Jan. 9, 1942; 15 (Box 15)
    - Hornaday, Clifford L., (1), Christmas, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
    - Huang, J.L., (1), June 12, 1947; 15 (Box 15)
    - Hubble, Jay B., (1), Feb. 3, 1955; 15 (Box 15)
  - J
    - Jenkins, Marys., (2), Nov. 28, 1940, n.d.; 15 (Box 15)
    - Jones, Howard M., (1), July 21, 1956; 15 (Box 15)
    - Jones, Louise Seymour, (1), Oct. 3, 1941; 15 (Box 15)
  - K
    - Kely, Jno. O., (1), n.d.; 15 (Box 15)
    - Kirkland, J.H., (2), Nov. 20, 1906, Dec. 4, 1934; 15 (Box 15)
    - Knight, Edgar W., (1), Sept. 22, 1926; 15 (Box 15)
    - Kodama, Kuni, (1), June 30, 1926; 15 (Box 15)
  - L
    - Lanier, Mary Day, (2), Dec. 17, 1903, June 9, 19o4; 15 (Box 15)
    - Laprade, W.T., (1), Mar. 7, 1952; 15 (Box 15)
    - Latham, Harold S., (2), Apr. 30, 1953, May 13, 1953; 15 (Box 15)
    - Lerner, Max, (1), Jan. 20, 1958; 15 (Box 15)
    - Leslie, Elmer T., (1), July 28, 1949; 15 (Box 15)
    - Loeke, W.T., (1), June 21, 1898; 15 (Box 15)
    - Longwell, Daniel, (3), June 3, 1926, n.d., n.d.; 15 (Box 15)
    - Lyman, Edward D., (1), Dec. 31, 1957; 15 (Box 15)
  - M
    - MacBeth, Jas. Currie, (1), Dec. 18, 1935; 15 (Box 15)
    - Mayfield, G.R., (1), Jan. 2, 1947; 15 (Box 15)
    - Miller, P.M., (1), Sept. 13; 15 (Box 15)
    - Mims, Edwin, Jr., (1), n.d.; 15 (Box 15)
    - Mims, Stewart, (1), Jan. 26, 1903; 15 (Box 15)
    - Mooney, C.P.J., (1), June 28, 1926; 15 (Box 15)
    - Moore, Frederick W., (2), Nov. 20, 1903, n.d. (fragment); 15 (Box 15)
    - Moore, Kate Gordon, (1), Dec. 28, 1955; 15 (Box 15)
    - Morgan, Hugh J., (2), Mar. 13, 1956, Dec. 6, 1956; 15 (Box 15)
    - Montgomery, Dinah Shore, (1), Jan. 12, 1954; 15 (Box 15)
    - Montgomery Walter A., (1), Nov. 18, 1908; 15 (Box 15)
    - Murray, John, (3), June 24, 1936, Feb. 10, 1939, Dec. 9, 1940; 15 (Box 15)
  - N
    - Nagel, Charles, (4), Apr. 8, 1933, May 5, 1933, May 3, 1934, May 28, 1935; 16 (Box 16)
    - Nenk, W.P., (2), Jan. 28, 1905, July 24, 1911; 16 (Box 16)
    - Nevinson, Henry W., (1), Apr. 19, 1936; 16 (Box 16)
    - Norman, H.F., (1), Apr. 4, 1936; 16 (Box 16)
  - O
    - Olson, Oscar Thomas, (1), Apr. 1, 1948; 16 (Box 16)
  - P
    - Page, Walter H., (7), Apr. 15, 1902, Nov. 28, 1904, Apr. 6, 1911, July 26, 1911, Aug. 18, 19ll,(with letter from C.P.M. to E.M. on reverse), Nov. 6, 1916, n;d. (fragment); 16 (Box 16)
    - Paschall, Walter, (1), Dec. 2, 1940; 16 (Box 16)
    - Perrow, E.C., (2), Jan. 10, 1955, Oct. 2, 1955; 16 (Box 16)
    - Perry, Bliss, (1), Nov. 12, 1941; 16 (Box 16)
    - Phillips, H.M., (1), Mar. 23, 1956; 16 (Box 16)
    - Poe, Clarence, (1), May 31, 1957; 16 (Box 16)
    - Purdy, R.R., (1), May 21, 1942; 16 (Box 16)
  - R
    - Ransom, John C., (3), July 6, 1924, Sept. 27, 1926, Nov. 13; 16 (Box 16)
    - Rawlings, Marjorie Kinnan, (2), Apr. 21, 1953, May 11, 1953; 16 (Box 16)
    - Rhett, R.G., (1), July 8, 1911; 16 (Box 16)
    - Robinson, Francis, (1), n.d.; 16 (Box 16)
    - Rouse, Blair, (1), Jan. 28, 1958; 16 (Box 16)
    - Rubey, S.C.A., (1), Dec. 9, 1926; 16 (Box 16)
    - Rueli, Latta, (1), June 15, 1898; 16 (Box 16)
    - Russell, Fred, (1), Feb. 3, 1958; 16 (Box 16)
  - S
    - Sarratt, Charles Madison, (1), Nov. 30, 1950; 16 (Box 16)
    - Shepley, Ethan, (1), Apr. 12, 1939; 16 (Box 16)
    - Smith, C. Alphonso, (2), Dec. 3, 1905, Dec. 4, 1911; 16 (Box 16)
    - Smith, Chas. F., (2), Sept. 9, 1895, Oct. 3, 1912; 16 (Box 16)
    - Snyder, Franklin B., (2), May 9, 1944, Mar. 22, 1948; 16 (Box 16)
    - Snyder, Henry Nelson, (2), Aug. 30, 1910, July 16, 1945; 16 (Box 16)
    - Southgate, J.K., (2), Jan. 1, 1913, May 2, 1916; 16 (Box 16)
    - Spence, H.E., (2), Mar. 18, 1956, Jan. 8, 1959; 16 (Box 16)
    - Stamp, J.C., (1), Dec. 17, 1937; 16 (Box 16)
    - Stephens, George, (1), Apr. 10, 1909; 16 (Box 16)
    - Stowe, Beecher, (1), July 12, 1926; 16 (Box 16)
    - Stuart, Jesse, (6), May 27, 1942, Oct. 3, 1943 (fragment), Mar. 21, 1955, Sept. 27, 1959, Christmas n.d., Christmas n.d.; 16 (Box 16)
    - Stewart, Randall, (5), Jan. 8, 1951, Feb. 1, 1954, Feb. 16, 1954, Feb. 24, 1954, Mar. 18, 1954; 16 (Box 16)
    - Swaun, Doris L., (1), Apr. 6, 1954; 16 (Box 16)
  - T
    - Thayer, William R., (1), Jan. 21, 1906; 16 (Box 16)
    - Thompson, R. Elmo, (1), Feb. 21, 1941; 16 (Box 16)
    - Tilley, Nannie M., (1), Nov. 2, 1943; 16 (Box 16)
    - Trent, W.P., (13), July 21, 1903, Aug. 9, 1903, Oct. 28, 1903, Jan. 23, 1905, Feb. 1, 1905, Mar. 1, 1905, Apr. 28, 1905, Dec. 28, 1905, July 15, 1906, Mar. 1, 1909, Feb. 28, 1912, Mar. 29, 1914, n.d.; 16 (Box 16)
    - Trimble, H.B., (1), Mar. 25, 1952; 16 (Box 16)
  - U
    - Udal, N.R., (1), May 14, 1936; 16 (Box 16)
  - V
    - Vance, Rupert B., (1), July 24, 1958; 16 (Box 16)
    - Vanderbilt, Harold S., (2), May 13, 1955; May 13, 1955; 16 (Box 16)
    - Venable, Francis P. (2), Feb. 27, 1912, Oct. 2?, 1913; 16 (Box 16)
    - Villard, Oswald Gamison, (1), Feb. 28, 1941; 16 (Box 16)
  - W
    - Ward, Judson C. Jr., (4), Mar. 10, 1955, Mar. 11, 1955, Apr. 2, 1956, May 24, 1956; 16 (Box 16)
    - Ware, Lowry, (1), Apr. 12, 1955; 16 (Box 16)
    - Watkins, Wilbur, (1), Nov. 15, 1949; 16 (Box 16)
    - Weaver, Richard M., (1), Aug. 29, 1958; 16 (Box 16)
    - Webb, Thompson, (1), June 29, 1957; 16 (Box 16)
    - Webb, W.R. and J.M., (2), Aug. 25, 1888, Apr. 5, 1907 (Box 16)
    - White, Goodrich C., (5), Mar. 1, 1952, Jan. 15, 1956, Feb. 21, 1956, Feb. 15, 1957, Feb. 5, 1958; 16 (Box 16)
    - Wiggins, B. LawtPn, (1), Dec. 5, 1908; 16 (Box 16)
    - Wilson, Louis R., (2), Jan. 14, 1932, June 5, 1957; 16 (Box 16)
    - Wolf., John Quincy, (1), Dec. 5, 1949; 16 (Box 16)
  - Y
    - Yancy, Stave (?), (1), n.d.; 16 (Box 16)
    - Young, Stark, (1), n.d. (Box 16)
    - Fragments - 3 (Box 16)
    - First name only - 1 "Lawrence" (Box 16)
    - Illegible - 2 (1 with E.M. letter to C.P.M. on reverse) (Box 16)
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous
  - Goodal, G.S. to Col. Fay W. Brabson, Apr. 8, 1920 (Box 16)
  - Hughes, Charles E. to Dr. Lyman Abbott, Jan.18, 1909 (Box 16)
  - Lanier, Mary Day to Mr. Richard Webb, May 11, 1903. (Box 16)
  - ______? to Cousin Herman, Nov. 21, 1933 (typed copy). (Box 16)
  - ______? to Mr. Eugene G. Steger, Apr. 16, 1935; (typed copy). (Box 16)
  - Langston, John D. to Rosalie, May 31, 1956, plus Langston's poems and miscellaneous writings. (Box 16)
  - Nagel Correspondence (Box 16)
  - Bryce, James to Mr. Nagel, Apr. 15, 1913 (Box 16)
  - Nock, Albert Jay to Mr. Nagle, Aug.30, 1926, Dec. 28, 1937, n.d. two fragments (Box 16)
  - "1882 - 1929 Addresses, Articles Etc. by Charles Nagel" (typed copy) (Box 16)
- Addresses - MSS
  - American literature (Box 16)
  - "Armistice Day Address" (Box 16)
  - "Bright Intervals" (incomplete) (Box 16)
  - Burns Dinner (Box 16)
  - "The Day We Celebrate" (Box 16)
  - Fisk University, 1933, 1937 (Box 16)
  - "The International Mind" (Box 16)
  - "Nashville, The Ideal City" (Box 16)
  - The New Humanism (Box 16)
  - "On Carrying Coals to Newcastle," et. al. (incomplete) (Box 16)
  - Southern Association 1955 (Box 16)
  - "The South Once More" (Box 16)
  - Addresses, miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Addresses, untitled (V.U.) (Box 16)
  - Addresses, extracts (Box 16)
  - The Advancing South, advertisements, statements, reviews (Box 16)
  - Adventurous America, comments on (Box 16)
  - Dr. Alderman, notes about (not by Mims) (Box 17)
  - ARTICLES, Misc. Published Writings about Mims: (arranged chronologically) (Box 17)
  - "Professor Mims at Vanderbilt," The Charlotte Observer., Nov. 10, 1900 (Box 17)
  - "The Richmond Conference," The Evening Post, N.Y., April 30, 1903 (Box 17)
  - "Limericks," Summer School Items, University of Virginia., July 17, 1909 (Box 17)
  - "Another Heavy Loss," Observer, Charlotte, N.C., Feb. 23, 1912 (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Edwin Mims," The Alumni Review, Vol. V, No. 2., Nov., 1916 (Box 17)
  - "American Literature - Triumph of National Spirit Described by Prof. Mims," (newspaper title fragmented)., July 11, 1921 (Box 17)
  - "Conflict in the South Is Outlined by Doctor Mims," New York Commercial., May 6, 1926 (Box 17)
  - "A Southern Liberal," The Nation, (review of The Advancing South)., June 30, 1926 (Box 17)
  - "Mims, Mencken, Mooney," Chattanooga Times., Aug.6, 1926 (Box 17)
  - "Heard and Seen " by Fuzzy Woodruff, The Atlanta Georgian., Dec. 10, 1926 (Box 17)
  - "The Literary Lantern," (fragmented newspaper title)., June 24, 1927 (Box 17)
  - "The Advancing South - The Sunday Afternoon Radio Address," The Christian Herald., Jan. 29, 1927 (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Mims Passes By," The Houston Gargoyle., Mar. 17, 1929 (Box 17)
  - "By the Book," (Review of Adventurous America), St. Louis Daily Globe-Democrat., Nov. 9, 1929 (Box 17)
  - "Criticism," (Critique of Adventurous America), American Mercury., Dec., 1929 (Box 17)
  - "Discussion of Edwin Mim's Adventurous America," by William S. Knickerbocker, Creative Reading - Discussions in Current Literature., Dec. 1, 1929 (Box 17)
  - "Still Optimistic," (Review of Adventurous America), Record, Greensboro, N.C., Dec. 4, 1929 (Box 17)
  - "English Professor Summarizes America's Present and Future," by W.G. Piersel, (Review of Adventurous America), Pantagraph, Bloomington, Ill., Jan.12, 1930 (Box 17)
  - "Where America is Going," (Review of Adventurous America and America Set Free by Count Hermann Keyserling), The Saturday Review., Feb. 8, 1930 (Box 17)
  - "Myths and Realities," by Arthur Colton (Review of Adventurous America), The Saturday Review (?)., Mar. 22, 1930 (Box 17)
  - ‘Review of Adventurous America, Nation's Business., April, 1930 (Box 17)
  - "Book Reviews, A Contemporary Study," (Review of Adventurous America), The West Australian, Perth, West Australia., May 10, 1930 (Box 17)
  - "A ‘Mildly Victorian' Professor Goes Out to Meet America," The New York Times Book Review., July 6, 1930 (Box 17)
  - "The Everlasting No - The Everlasting Yea," Public Opinion., Aug. 22, 1930 (Box 17)
  - "Literature of America - Visiting Professor's First Lecture of Series," The Citizen, St. Andrews, Scotland., Oct. 12, 1935 (Box 17)
  - "An Interesting Visitor, Professor Mims, Tennessee, in St. Andrews," The Citizen., Oct. 26, 1935 (Box 17)
  - "The Southern States - Parallel with Ireland, Professor Mim's Lecture," The Irish Times., Nov. 15, 1935 (Box 17)
  - "Our English Cousins' Talents for Citizenship," (no newspaper title)., Dec. 6, 1936 (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Edwin Mims Writes of Some Impressions Here During Summer," Duke Alumni Register., Oct., 1938 (Box 17)
  - "Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt," The President's Page by S.C. Garrison, The Peabody Reflector and Alumni News., ca. 1940 (Box 17)
  - "The University's New Venture," Vanderbilt Alumnus, Vol. XXVI, No. 2., Nov., 1940 (Box 17)
  - "Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt, A Review," by John L. Hill, The Vanderbilt Alumnus., Dec., 1940 (Box 17)
  - "Careful Craftsmanship Mims' Biography of Chancellor Kirkland Inaugurates Vanderbilt University Press," by John L. Hill (Review of Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt), The Nashville Banner., Dec. 11, 1940 (Box 17)
  - "From the Shoulder," by James G. Stahlman, The Nashville Banner, Dec. 16, 1940 (Box 17)
  - "Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt Lives in This Book," by M.C. Huntley, (Review of Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt) The Birmingham News - Age - Herald. (2 copies)., Feb. 2, 1941 (Box 17)
  - "Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt; The South's Educational Statesman," by Jean Fligg, (Review of Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt), Knoxville Journal, Feb. 2, 1941 (Box 17)
  - Letter to the Editor from Allen Tate, Vanderbilt Alumnus., Mar. 1, 1941 (Box 17)
  - "Biography of Chancellor Kirkland Important, Interesting Picture of Education in South," by Paul L. Palmer, (Review of Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt), The Chattanooga Times., Mar. 2, 1941 (Box 17)
  - "Story of a Great Life," by John Erskine, (Review of Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt), New York Herald Tribune, (3 copies)., Aug. 24, 1941 (Box 17)
  - "Colleagues Now Retired," Editorial, The Vanderbilt Alumnus., June, 1942 (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Mims Honored at Dinner For Contribution to Education," The Nashville Banner., May 27, 1942 (Box 17)
  - "Vanderbilt's Growth From Small College," by David A. Lockmiller, (A Review of History of Vanderbilt University), Chattnooga Times., "early" 1943 (Box 17)
  - "Distinguished History of Vanderbilt," by Robert Selph Henry, (Review of History of V.U.), The Nashville Banner., Oct. 30, 1946 (Box 17)
  - "Vanderbilt's History Told In Terms of Men From There," by W.C. Teague, (Review of History of V.U.), Commercial Appeal, Memphis, Tn., Dec. 29, 1946 (Box 17)
  - "Man Thinking." Rollins College Paper., Feb. 27, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Mims Discusses ‘Flowering' of Culture in New England," The Nashville Banner. (2 copies)., July 30, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Mims Cites Wholesome Provincialism in Literature," The Nashville Banner., Aug. 1, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "Ulysses Emeritus - He Is Still Around," The Alumnus., March, 1948 (Box 17)
  - "Vandy Dynamo ‘Retirement' Fails to Slow Edwin Mims," The Atlanta Constitution., April 1, 1948 (Box 17)
  - "Edwin Mims: Professor-at-Large, He Has Been Classed Among the Three Greatest Teachers America Has Produced in the Twentieth Century," The Alumnus. (2 copies, one of which is fragmented.), June, 1949 (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Edwin Mims, 83, Is Busier Than Ever," by Ralph McGill, The Atlanta Constitution (This is a copy of a typed excerpt from an editorial by Ralph McGill)., Dec., 1953 (Box 17)
  - "After Deciding to Teach ‘It Was Like A New Heaven And a New Earth'," Durham Morning Herald, Durham, N.C. (On same page is an introduction of Dr. Mirna by Chancellor R.B. House of Duke Univ.)., Mar. 4, 1956 (Box 17)
  - N.D.'s- arranged alphabetically by title: (Box 17)
  - "Address Delivered By Dr. Edwin Mims of Vanderbilt University At The Memorial Exercs Held at West Erid Methodist Church, Nashville, Feb. 11," Peabody Alumni News. (Box 17)
  - "American Literature - Achievement of the West - Effect of Environment," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "America's Part ‘To a Better Internationalism' Woodrow Wilson's Dream," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "Among Us Tar Heels," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "Anglo-American Relations - The Importance of Literature - Some Suggested Books," letter of J.C. Stamp to the Editor of The Times, London. (Box 17)
  - "Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt," A Review by Edgar W. Knight, The High School Journal. (Box 17)
  - "Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt," A Review by E.J.R., Christian Advocate. (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Edwin Mims Leads On Quest of High Adventures," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "Dr. Edwin Mims Praised For His Frank Analysis Of Conditions In South," (Review of The Advancing South), Charleston News and Courier. (Box 17)
  - "Englische Studien," (Review of The Advancing South) by Friedrich Brie Hoops (?). (Box 17)
  - "Four Teachers, Total Age of 283, In New Posts, Come Out of Retirement and Join the New School and Teach for a Semester," Herald Tribune, Oct. 10. (Box 17)
  - "The Frontier of The Spirit: The Firing-Line of The Soul," The Birmingham News. (Box 17)
  - "Golden Age of Boston, St. Andrews University Lecture - Professor Edwin Mirna," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "A Great American Hellenist: Professor Basil L. Gildersleeve," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "A Great Educator," (Review of Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt) by Alexander Guerry (no journal title). (Box 17)
  - "A History of Vanderbilt University," (Review of History of V.U.) by Hill Turner, Vanderbilt Alumnus Reprint. (Box 17)
  - "I Reckon So," by T.H. Alexander, The Nashville Tennessean(?). (Box 17)
  - "Ideal And Material In South's Life," Nashville Banner. (Box 17)
  - "Fifty Years of Intellectual Progress," Incidentally (column) by Nell Battle Lewis (3 copies). (Box 17)
  - "International Mind in America Stressed in Dr. Mims' Lecture," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "Letters and Life - In which books, plays and people are discussed," editea by Leon Whipple (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "Literature as a Nation Builder, A Review of the Mims Lecture Course," The League Script (?). (Box 17)
  - "Mencken Boycott Urged By Dr. Mims - Vanderbilt Professor Lectures in New York on ‘Cult of Smartness," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "On Shakespeare Jury," picture and caption, The __?_____ Courier. (Box 17)
  - "An Optimistic Outlook," (Review of Adventurous America), The Cornell Alumni News. (Box 17)
  - "Outlook," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "Scotland and U.S. - Influence on American Life and Letters - St. Andrew's Lecture," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "Southerners Asked to End Fighting War - Dr. Edwin Mims Advocates Following Lee's Banner to New Era - South's Two Needs - Criticism and Larger Freedom of Thought Recommended," (no newspaper title). (Box 17)
  - "University Day - The One Hundred and Twenty-Third Anniversary is Fittingly Observed," The Alumni Review. (Box 17)
  - "The Youthful Mr. Mims," The Chapel Hill Weekly. (Box 17)
    Also included are typed excerpts from miscellaneous articles about Mims and/or his work, 1925 - 1926, (3 pages), and numerous fragments of articles which are not indexed.
  - "Scraps and Fragments," in The Vanderbilt Observer, Vol. XV, No.5 (E. Mims, Editor-In-Chief). May also have written the editorial. Entire issue intact., Feb., 1893 (Box 17)
  - "Shakespeare's One Farcical Comedy," The Chigago Record., Oct.16, 1899 (Box 17)
  - "Some Observations on Reading," Charlotte Daily Observer., Nov. 11, 1906 (Box 17)
  - "Woodrow Wilson, The Hsppy Warrior," reprint from The Methodist Quarterly Review., April, 1924 (Box 17)
  - "Mark Twain's Autobiography Season's Most Disappointing Book," The Tennessean., Jan. 4, 1925 (Box 17)
  - "The Humanizing of Literature," reprint from The English Journal, Vol. XIV, No. 6., June, 1925 (Box 17)
  - "The Humanities: Past and Present," reprints from Southern Association Quarterly., August, 1939 (Box 17)
  - "John Maurice Webb (1847- 1916), 11 in Webb School in Celebration of Its 75th Birthday., ca. 1949 (Box 17)
  - "Sixty Years in a Classroom," Durham Morning Herald, Durham, N.C., March 4, 1956 (Box 17)
  - "A Southern Rebel Agctinst Romanticism," (Review of Letters of Ellen Glasgow, edited by Blair Rouse), The Nashville Banner., Jan. 17, 1958 (Box 17)
  - "Some By-Products of the Anti-Evolution Law," The Nashville Tennessean., n.d. (Box 17)
  - Article about Robert E. Lee, condensed from an address given by Mims on the 80th ann;versary of Lee's death., n.d. (Box 17)
- Autobiography
  - "A Forward" (Box 17)
  - "A Frontier Community" (Box 17)
  - "A Unique and Famous School" (Box 17)
  - "Formative Influences at Vanderbilt University, (1888 - 1894)" (Box 17)
  - "Teaching in a Denominational College" (Box 17)
  - "A Year at Cornell ..." (Box 17)
  - "Education in North Carolina " (Box 17)
  - "The Grand Tour" (Box 17)
  - "A Bright Interval" (Box 18)
  - "The Return to Alma Mater" (Box 18)
  - "Scholars, Critics and Creative Writers..." (Box 18)
  - "The Advancing South" (Box 18)
  - "In Search of America" (Box 18)
  - "Yaddo, An Artistic Colony" (Box 18)
  - "Widening Horizons" (Box 18)
  - "Adventurous America" (Box 18)
  - "Visiting Professor in Great Britain " (Box 18)
  - "A Harvest of Letters" (Box 18)
  - "The Second Prime of Life" (Box 18)
  - "Terminus? No!" (Box 18)
  - Chancellor Kirkland of Vanderbilt - Advertisements, Reviews (Box 18)
  - Class Lectures (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Clippings, misc. published material collected by Mims: (arranged chronologically) (Box 18)
    ca. July, 1896, "Liberty, Justice, Equality," leaflet in support of the Bentley-Southgate Ticket.
    July 7, 1900, "The Ticket and Platform for the Observer's Position," (no newspaper title).
    May 15, 1909, The Outlook, Vol. 92, No. 3. (entire issue intact).
    ca. June, 1915, "Dedicated to Chancellor St. Judas and The Trustees of Kirknegiebilt University. With Apologies to Mr. G. Byron" (no source listed).
  - "Woodrow Wilson's Place in History," by Jan Christian Smuts. (no journal title)., ca. 1921 (Box 18)
  - "The Impact of Science Upon Society," by Sir Josiah Stamp, British Association for the Advancement of Society - Blackpool, 1936; The Presidential Address., 1936 (Box 18)
  - "Parliament" (News Reviews), The Times, London., March 27, 1936 (Box 18)
  - "The Moderate Nan Is At A Discount," Public Opinion, Address by Lord Tweedsmuir, Governor-General of Canada., Jan. 8, 1937 (Box 18)
  - "Death of Mr. Edward Garnett," The Manchester Guardian (?)., Feb. 26, 1939 (Box 18)
  - "‘Sawney Webb'," by William R. Webb, Jr. Reprinted from April Number of The Sewanee Review., 1942 (Box 18)
  - The Key Reporter - The Phi Beta Kappa News Magazine, Vol. XX, No. 2., Feb. 1955 (Box 18)
  - "The South and Integration:'South's Worst Qualities Have Come Out'," An interview with Mark Ethridge, Publisher Louisville Courier Journal, The Nashville Banner., March 13, 1956 (Box 18)
  - "The Middle of the Road - Where It Leads," by Richard M. Weaver, Human Events., March 24, 1956 (Box 18)
  - "We Will Not Close Our Schools," by Jonathan Daniels, North Carolina Education., Jan. 1959 (Box 18)
- N.D.'S
  - "As Calhoun Lay Dying," by Ralph McGill. (Box 18)
  - "Do Reds Make Blues Blue?," by Dudley Meads MacKegg. (Box 18)
  - "Lux Mundi," Incidentally (column) by Nell Battle Lewis (Box 18)
  - "The Institute and Our Industrial Development," by Henry M. Robinson. (Box 18)
  - "Loncoln: A Southern View," by Archibald Rutledge, The Reviewer. (Box 18)